Glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses.
Glasses, glasses, glasses.
Glasses, glasses...
Glasses!
Glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses!
Glasses, glasses, glasses...
glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses!
Nichijou Part 78
I'd like to do something that has never been seen before, and will never be seen again!
Domestic violence.
How was it?
What am I supposed to say?
It was very much like you.
It really was.
Yes, just like you.
Then next, I'll do something not like me.
I tripped!
That was just like her...
Just like her.
Newbie Part 1
How about some rice cakes! Come get your rice cakes.
I'm sorry, but do you think you could wear this?
How about some rice cakes! Come get your rice cakes!
Sorry, but could you stop talking?
Newbie Part 2
Can't you wear some clothes?
Are you sulking?!
Newbie Part 3
You're not sulking? So, what is it?
Hey... You can talk now!
Like Love
I hope I get accepted to Tokisadame High School.
I hope the person above gets accepted.
I hope the person to the right gets accepted...
I hope the person below gets accepted!! You can do it!
Nichijou Part 79
Here I go!
Yes!
You didn't jump!
Huh? But the bar...
Yes, but you didn't jump over it!
How many times do I have to teach you?
The sun's going to set!
Sorry. I'll try harder this time.
This time, I'll lower the bar.
Take your time.
Just be sure you do it just like I taught you, okay?
Okay.
I have to be able to jump before the next test...
Or everyone's going to laugh at me!
How was that?
You stupid cow!
Why won't you jump the way I taught you?
Are you messing around?
In my mind, it was a perfect Fosbury Flop.
A perfect Fosbury Flop?
Your form's closer to...
a fish's!
A human fish...
I didn't say that!
No, I...
I guess I did say that...
No, no, no. You're just kidding.
Don't you realize what you're doing?
Sorry.
Well, I'll stay until you're satisfied.
You always let me copy your homework.
It's my turn to help you!
Let's keep going until you can do it.
Just take it slowly...
First, try to jump as if you're just stepping over it!
Calm down, Mio-chan! It's okay!
It isn't that I've suddenly become non-athletic.
Go! You can do it!
Hey, Mio-chan... We're playing soccer!
I'm as fit as the average person.
But when rules get involved, I lose control.
Backwards fall...
Go!
Mio-chan, the other way! You're doing it in reverse!
If I do nothing, nothing will change.
I'll just stay as I am!
Ready, and...
Mio-chan, backflip. Not propeller!
I don't care if it's pointless...
I don't care if I don't get results.
There's only one thing I can do...
One, two, three!
Let's give it another try.
For Yukko...
I'm going to take a break.
Okay.
For myself, too!
I won't give up! If I have to give up...
I'll make sure I've done everything I could first!
Hard work will always open doors.
This came    This came
A
This came to be known as the "fish flop."
to be known as
the "fish flop."
This is a White Tiger
This is a white tiger.
All they do is sleep...
That one's pointing its butt at us.
Yeah.
They're really far away, too. It's hard to see.
We came all this way to see them, and it's boring!
We should be glad we got to see them.
I guess...
Hooray!
Nichijou Part 80
It's raining! We should bring in the laundry.
Hey, where are you going?
Yay!
It's too late already.
Just get it inside!
It's raining!
Professor, Sakamoto-san, I'm home...
It's raining hard, isn't it?
Did you bring in the laundry?
Sakamoto told me to bring it in!
It's true.
Sakamoto really did tell me to bring it in...
Does Sakamoto-san telling you to bring in the laundry make you drop it?
No! Sakamoto told me to bring it in...
and drop it.
I did not!
That was shocking...
What were you talking about, kid?
You told me to do it!
I never told you to drop it.
Did, too!
Did not!
Give me a break...
What?!
Nano... Let's sacrifice Sakamoto. Then everything'll be okay, right?
What's going on?
Forget it. We can just wash it again.
Oh! Right.
That's right.
But we can never get back this day.
Neither of you gets dinner tonight.
What?
How did I get dragged into this?
Sakamoto did it! And I said I'd sacrifice Sakamoto.
That's okay, right?
Fine. Then I'll take Sakamoto-san.
And you won't get any dinner, Professor.
What?
No! Then I'll sacrifice myself!
I dropped it! I'm the one who got it wet...
What?
Ta-dah! Today's dinner is omelette rice!
Wow...
The eggs were on sale.
Huh? Do I get to eat today?
Oh! That's right. I completely forgot...
Um, well...
Well, let's just eat today!
Hooray!
No dinner tomorrow.
Lame.
Swim, swim.
Shark, shark, chomp.
What is this?
Mio-chan! Mai-chan! Selamat pagi!
Didn't that self-portrait sculpture assignment suck?
What? That's due today?
What's this? Mio-sensei, did you forget your homework?
I thought it was due tomorrow.
Mai-chan, did you do it?
Oh, no.
Mai-chan didn't do hers, either?
Looks like we might see more rain...
It won't just be a shower.
It'll be a catastrophe!
Nichijou Part 81
It really did start...
...to rain.
What have you done to my temple?
You thieves...
Th-That was close!
It's a curse...
It's an evil spirit.
B-Begone...
Leave this temple!
"Let us go."
Is what they thought as the autumn rain fell.
Nichijou Part 82
Please, President...
I'm about to have a match against Takasaki-sensei.
Won't you be our referee?
Referee? You mean for igo soccer?
Yes!
If I win, he has to become our advisor.
I know I can do it!
What do I have to do?
It's okay.
Everything you need to know is in the igo soccer guide I lent you.
It's my fault for not reading the guide, but...
I have no idea what they've been doing...
This is igo soccer?
You wouldn't understand, even if you'd read the guide.
Ogi?
Neither is observing the rules.
Their high-level play has no regard for theory.
If that outstretched hand is the leg of a Go board,
that stance is the stone.
It may appear normal at first glance, but that ball between his feet is an anomaly.
It's just speculation, but I believe these two...
are trying to achieve brilliance!
I have no idea what he's talking about.
There they go!
Oh, no!
Birabudo!
Ogi, what does that...
Quiet!
Can't you see how the air flows between them?
Someone may even die.
What's going on?
I haven't seen such high-level play in a long time.
No wonder the wind screams...
No! That stance!
Could it be?
Would he really use that move in an unofficial match?
Is he out of his mind?
I cannot allow this to happen...
Father, I must do it!
All in the name of justice...
I must become a shining star!
Ogi Forbidden Technique...
Ogi-boshi!
This is a final rabudo!
Not bad...
You, too, sensei.
Unbelievable...
When I founded this club, I didn't give it much thought.
I can't believe...
this is happening.
Short Thoughts
Free for Employees
I take a break
when no one sees me.
I take a break when no one sees me.
No matter how many times you step on me, you won't kill me!
I'm clay.
Show some respect!
Today, I'll change into various forms again to battle the children!
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 20.
Narration: Mitsuya Yuji
Now, go challenge those children!